Builders Exchange of St. Paul records
University of Minnesota Libraries
Builders Exchange of St. Paul records
1909-1994
Builders Exchange of St. Paul
University of Minnesota Libraries. Northwest Architectural Archives, Manuscripts Division [naa]
7 boxes (9.1 linear feet)
Collection contains bound copies of minutes of Board of Directors meetings (1909-ongoing), and bound copies of the Weekly Newsletter (1912-ongoing).
N 62
Administrative Information
Restrictions on Access
Available for use in the Manuscripts Division reading room. Advance notice is requested.
Acquisition
The collection was donated to the Northwest Architectural Archives by Roger E. Miller on January 18, 1978.
Accruals
The Builders Exchange binds each year's accumulation of Board minutes and newsletters and retains the last 10 years' issues. As each volume becomes older than 10 years, it is deposited in the collection each January of the succeeding year.
Arrangement
The collection is organized into two series:
Minutes
Newsletters
Historical Note
The Builders Exchange of St. Paul is a membership organization of contractors, architects, building tradesmen and suppliers of building materials. Through their support, the Exchange functions as a center in which prints of plans for buildings newly designed by architects may be consulted by contractors and subcontractors in order to compile their bid estimates. It also acts as a source for information about the services offered by contractors and suppliers who are located in the area.
Scope and Content Note
The collection contains bound copies of minutes of Board of Directors meetings, from 1909 to within ten years of the present date, and bound copies of the Weekly Newsletter for the years 1912 until a decade ago. The Newsletter carries news of the Builders Exchange and its members, plans on file and available for bid and notice of contracts awarded.
Additional Finding Aid
An unpublished finding aid with detailed contents is available in the Manuscripts Division.
Index Terms
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the catalog of the University of Minnesota Libraries. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Builders Exchange of St. Paul -- Archives; Construction industry -- Minnesota -- Saint Paul; Building estimates -- Minnesota
- Minutes
  - December 28, 1900 - March 22, 1902 (Box 01)
  - April 22, 1902 - January 6, 1903 (Box 01)
  - January 20, 1903 - January 5, 1904 (Box 01)
  - February 2, 1904 - February 7, 1905 (Box 01)
  - March 7, 1905 - December 5, 1905 (Box 01)
  - January 2, 1906 - November 6, 1906 (Box 01)
  - December 4, 1906 - March 5, 1907 (Box 01)
  - March 19, 1907 - January 21, 1908 (Box 01)
  - January 28, 1908 - December 30, 1909 (Box 02)
  - January 5, 1909 - December 22, 1909 (Box 02)
  - January 4, 1910 - January 17, 1911 (Box 02)
  - February 7, 1911 - June 4, 1912 (Box 02)
  - July 2, 1912 - July 8, 1913 (Box 02)
  - July 22, 1913 - June 2, 1914 (Box 02)
  - July 7, 1914 - December 7, 1915 (Box 02)
  - December 21, 1915 - December 5, 1916 (Box 03)
  - December 5, 1916 - December 18, 1917 (Box 03)
  - January 8, 1918 - October 14, 1919 (Box 03)
  - November 4, 1919 - December 19, 1922 (Box 03)
  - January 4, 1923 - December 16, 1924 (Box 03)
  - December 27, 1924 - December 3, 1926 (Box 03)
  - December 7, 1926 - June 15, 1928 (Box 03)
  - July 28, 1928 - January 23, 1930 (Box 04)
  - March 12, 1930 - February 4, 1932 (Box 04)
  - March 9, 1932 - December 1, 1933 (Box 04)
  - December 5, 1933 - August 7, 1935 (Box 04)
  - November 5, 1935 - December 31, 1936 (Box 04)
  - February 1, 1937 - February 27, 1937 (Box 04)
  - June 5, 1939 - August 4, 1941 (Box 04)
  - August 29, 1941 - October 27, 1942 (Box 05)
  - December 8, 1942 - November 15, 1943 (Box 05)
  - December 7, 1943 - November 30, 1944 (Box 05)
  - December 5, 1944 - November 30, 1945 (Box 05)
  - December 1, 1945 - November 30, 1946 (Box 05)
  - December 1, 1946 - November 30, 1947 (Box 05)
  - December 1, 1947 - November 30, 1948 (Box 05)
  - December 1, 1948 - November 30, 1949 (Box 05)
  - December 1, 1949 - November 30, 1950 (Box 05)
  - December 1, 1950 - November 30, 1951 (Box 05)
  - December 1, 1952 - November 30, 1953 (Box 05)
  - December 1, 1953 - November 30, 1954 (Box 05)
  - December 1, 1954 - November 30, 1955 (Box 05)
  - December 13, 1955 - November 30, 1956 (Box 05)
  - December 1, 1956 - November 30, 1957 (Box 05)
  - December 1, 1957 - November 30, 1958 (Box 05)
  - November 30, 1958 - December 8, 1959 (Box 05)
  - December 8, 1959 - December 8, 1960 (Box 06)
  - December 13, 1960 - December 8, 1961 (Box 06)
  - October 16, 1961 - December 11, 1962 (Box 06)
  - December 11, 1962 - December 10, 1963 (Box 06)
  - December 10, 1963 - November 30, 1964 (Box 06)
  - December 8, 1964 - November 30, 1965 (Box 06)
  - October 30, 1965 - October 31, 1966 (Box 06)
  - December 13, 1966 - October 31, 1967 (Box 06)
  - October 31, 1967 - November 29, 1968 (Box 06)
  - December 10, 1968 - December 15, 1969 (Box 06)
  - November 24, 1969 - December 8, 1970 (Box 06)
  - November 23, 1970 - October 19, 1971 (Box 06)
  - November 11, 1971 - October 9, 1972 (Box 06)
  - December 12, 1972 - October 15, 1973 (Box 06)
  - November 8, 1973 - October 15, 1974 (Box 06)
  - November 8, 1974 - October 13, 1975 (Box 06)
  - November 17, 1975 - October 11, 1976 (Box 07)
  - October 31, 1976 - October 11, 1977 (Box 07)
  - October 31, 1977 - October 9, 1978 (Box 07)
  - November 1, 1978 - October 15, 1979 (Box 07)
  - November 6, 1979 - October 22, 1980 (Box 07)
  - November 17, 1980 - October 20, 1981 (Box 07)
  - November 5, 1981 - October 18, 1982 (Box 07)
  - November 3, 1982 - October 19, 1983 (Box 07)
  - November 3, 1983 - September 19, 1984 (Box 07)
  - October 31, 1984 - September 17, 1985 (Box 07)
  - November 11, 1985 - October 28, 1986 (Box 07)
  - November 4, 1986 - October 31, 1987 (Box 07)
  - November 5, 1987 - September 21, 1988 (Box 07)
  - November 14, 1988 - October 10, 1989 (Box 07)
  - November, 1989 - October, 1990 (Box 07)
  - November, 1990 - October 1991 (Box 07)
  - November, 1991 - October, 1992 (Box 07)
  - November, 1992- October, 1993 (Box 07)
  - November, 1993- October, 1994 (Box 07)
  - November 1994- October, 1995 (Box 07)
  - November, 1995- October 1996 (Box 07)
  - November 1996- October, 1997 (Box 07)
  - November, 1997- October 1998 (Box 07)
  - November, 1998- October, 1999 (Box 07)
- Newsletters
  - March 18, 1912 - March 10, 1913 (Box 01)
  - March 17, 1913 - April 13, 1914 (Box 01)
  - April 20, 1914 - April 19, 1915 (Box 01)
  - April 26, 1915 - March 13, 1916 (Box 01)
  - June 1915 - December 1918 (Monthly letter) (Box 01)
  - March 20, 1916 to November 20, 1916 (Box 01)
  - November 27, 1916 - October 1, 1917 (Box 01)
  - October 8, 1917 - June 3, 1918 (Box 01)
  - June 10, 1918 - June 30, 1919 (Box 01)
  - July 7, 1919 - June 1, 1920 (Box 01)
  - September 1920 - March 1921 (monthly newsletter) (Box 01)
  - June 7, 1921 - March 13, 1922 (Box 01)
  - March 20, 1922 - October 20, 1922 (Box 01)
  - November 6, 1922 - March 19, 1923 (Box 01)
  - March 26, 1923 - October 29, 1923 (Box 01)
  - November 5, 1923 - March 17, 1924 (Box 01)
  - March 24, 1924 - August 25, 1924 (Box 01)
  - September 2, 1924 - January 26, 1925 (Box 02)
  - June 1, 1925 - October 26, 1925 (Box 02)
  - February 2, 1925 - June 1, 1925 (Box 02)
  - November 2, 1925 - March 29, 1926 (Box 02)
  - September 6, 1926 - December 28, 1926 (Box 02)
  - April 5, 1926 - August 30, 1926 (Box 02)
  - January 3, 1927 - March 28, 1927 (Box 02)
  - April 4, 1927 - June 27, 1927 (Box 02)
  - July 5, 1927 - September 26, 1927 (Box 02)
  - October 3, 1927 - January 4, 1928 (Box 02)
  - January 2, 1928 - March 26, 1928 (Box 02)
  - April 2, 1928 - June 25, 1928 (Box 02)
  - July 2, 1928 - September 24, 1928 (Box 02)
  - October 1, 1928 - December 31, 1928 (Box 02)
  - January 7, 1929 - March 25, 1929 (Box 02)
  - April 1, 1929 - June 24, 1929 (Box 02)
  - July 1, 1929 - September 30, 1929 (Box 02)
  - October 7, 1929 - December 30, 1929 (Box 02)
  - January 6, 1930 - May 26, 1930 (Box 02)
  - June 2, 1930 - September 28, 1930 (Box 02)
  - October 6, 1930 - January 19, 1931 (Box 02)
  - January 26, 1931 - June 29, 1931 (Box 02)
  - July 6, 1931 -December 28, 1931 (Box 02)
  - January 4, 1932 - December 27, 1932 (Box 03)
  - January 3, 1933 - December 26, 1933 (Box 03)
  - January 1, 1934 - December 31, 1934 (Box 03)
  - March 11, 1935 - December 30, 1935 (Box 03)
  - January 6, 1936 - December 28, 1936 (Box 03)
  - January 4, 1937 - December 27, 1937 (Box 03)
  - January 3, 1938 - December 26, 1938 (Box 03)
  - January 3, 1939 - September 11, 1939 (Box 03)
  - January 2, 1940 - December 30, 1940 (Box 03)
  - January 6, 1941 - December 29, 1941 (Box 03)
  - January 5, 1942 - March 8, 1943 (Box 04)
  - March 15, 1943 - February 7, 1944 (Box 04)
  - February 14, 1944 - April 30, 1945 (Box 04)
  - May 7, 1945 - December 31, 1945 (Box 04)
  - January 7, 1946 - December 30, 1946 (Box 04)
  - January 6, 1947 - December 29, 1947 (Box 04)
  - January 5, 1948 - December 27, 1948 (Box 04)
  - January 3, 1949 - December 26, 1949 (Box 04)
  - January 2, 1950 - December 25, 1950 (Box 04)
  - January 1, 1950 - December 31, 1951 (Box 04)
  - January 7, 1952 - December 29, 1952 (Box 04)
  - January 5, 1953 - December 28, 1953 (Box 05)
  - January 5, 1954 - December 27, 1954 (Box 05)
  - January 3, 1955 - December 26, 1955 (Box 05)
  - January 2, 1956 - December 31, 1956 (Box 05)
  - January 7, 1957 - December 30, 1957 (Box 05)
  - January 6, 1958 - December 29, 1958 (Box 05)
  - January 5, 1959 - December 28, 1959 (Box 05)
  - January 4, 1960 - December 26, 1960 (Box 05)
  - January 2, 1961 - December 25, 1961 (Box 06)
  - January 1, 1962 - December 31, 1962 (Box 06)
  - January 7, 1963 - December 30, 1963 (Box 06)
  - January 6, 1964 - December 28, 1964 (Box 06)
  - January 4, 1965 - December 27, 1965 (Box 06)
  - January 3, 1966 - December 26, 1966 (Box 06)
  - January 2, 1967 - December 25, 1967 (Box 06)
  - January 1, 1968 - December 30, 1968 (Box 07)
  - January 6, 1969 - December 29, 1969 (Box 07)
  - January 5, 1970 - December 28, 1970 (Box 07)
  - January 4, 1971 - December 27, 1971 (Box 07)
  - January 3, 1972 - December 25, 1972 (Box 07)
  - January 1, 1973 - December 31, 1973 (Box 07)
  - January 7, 1974 - December 30, 1974 (Box 07)
  - January 6, 1975 - December 29, 1975 (Box 08)
  - January 5, 1976 - December 27, 1976 (Box 08)
  - January 3, 1977 - December 26, 1977 (Box 08)
  - January 2, 1978 - December 25, 1978 (Box 08)
  - January 1, 1979 - December 31, 1979 (Box 08)
  - January 7, 1980 - December 29, 1980 (Box 08)
  - January 5, 1981 - December 28, 1981 (Box 09)
  - January 4, 1982 - December 27, 1982 (Box 09)
  - January 3, 1983 - December 26, 1983 (Box 09)
  - January 2, 1984 - December 31, 1984 (Box 09)
  - January 7, 1985 - December 30, 1985 (Box 10)
  - January 6, 1986 - December 29, 1986 (Box 10)
  - January 5, 1987 - December 28, 1987 (Box 10)
  - 1914 - 1964 VL. 1 (History of Bowling League) (Box 10)
  - 1963 - 1988 VL. 2 (History of Bowling League) (Box 10)
  - January 4, 1988 - December 26, 1988 (Box 10)
  - January 2, 1989 - December 25, 1989 (Box 11)
  - January 8, 1990 - December 31, 1990 (Box 11)
  - January 7, 1991 - December 30, 1991 (Box 11)
  - January ?, 1992 - December ?, 1992 (Box 11)
  - January 19, 1993- December 27, 1993 (Box 11)
  - January 3 1994- December 20, 1994 (Box 11)
  - January 9, 1995- December 25, 1995 (Box 12)
  - January 1, 1996- December 30, 1996 (Box 12)
  - January 6, 1996- December 29, 1997 (Box 12)
  - January 5, 1998- December 28, 1998 (Box 12)
  - January 7, 1998 รป December 27, 1999 (Box 12)